<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Escutia Blog</title>
        <link>https://escutia.me/adrian</link>
        <description>Escutia Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 15:16:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fixing VS Code/Code.exe: Exec format error in WSL]]></title>
            <link>https://escutia.me/adrian/fixing-vscode-code.exe--exec-format-error-in-wsl</link>
            <guid>https://escutia.me/adrian/fixing-vscode-code.exe--exec-format-error-in-wsl</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 15:16:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[How to fix the Exec format error when trying to open VS Code from WSL.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From time to time, we run into issues that seem trivial but can be quite frustrating, when VS Code doesn't open from WSL, it can be one of those issues and it happens after a Windows update or a VS Code update. Here's how to fix it.</p>
<p>I recently ran into an issue where I couldn't open Visual Studio Code from WSL. I would get the following error:</p>
<div class="language-bash codeBlockContainer_Ckt0 theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#393A34;--prism-background-color:#f6f8fa"><div class="codeBlockContent_biex"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-bash codeBlock_bY9V thin-scrollbar" style="color:#393A34;background-color:#f6f8fa"><code class="codeBlockLines_e6Vv"><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">$ code .</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">/c/Users/adria/AppData/Local/Programs/Microsoft VS Code/bin/code: 61: /c/Users/adria/AppData/Local/Programs/Microsoft VS Code/Code.exe: Exec format error</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup__atx"><button type="button" aria-label="Copy code to clipboard" title="Copy" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_eSgA" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_y97N"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_LjdS"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div>
<p>Read on to learn how to fix this issue.</p>
<p>This error is due to the fact that the Windows executable is not compatible with the Linux environment. The solution is to create a symbolic link to the Windows executable from the Linux environment. The solution is simple, but it can be frustrating if you don't know what to do, eventually, you might end up reinstalling VS Code or even WSL; don't do that, I got you covered.</p>
<p>Here's how to fix it:</p>
<div class="language-bash codeBlockContainer_Ckt0 theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#393A34;--prism-background-color:#f6f8fa"><div class="codeBlockContent_biex"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-bash codeBlock_bY9V thin-scrollbar" style="color:#393A34;background-color:#f6f8fa"><code class="codeBlockLines_e6Vv"><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">$  sudo sh -c 'echo :WSLInterop:M::MZ::/init:PF &gt; /usr/lib/binfmt.d/WSLInterop.conf'</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">[sudo] password for $USER:</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">$  sudo systemctl unmask systemd-binfmt.service</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">$  sudo systemctl restart systemd-binfmt</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">$  sudo systemctl mask systemd-binfmt.service</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">Created symlink /etc/systemd/system/systemd-binfmt.service → /dev/null.</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">$ code .</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup__atx"><button type="button" aria-label="Copy code to clipboard" title="Copy" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_eSgA" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_y97N"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_LjdS"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div>
<p>That's it! You should now be able to open Visual Studio Code from WSL without any issues. If you still have issues, try restarting your WSL session.</p>
<p>I hope this helps you fix the issue. If you have any questions or comments, feel free to reach out, <a href="https://go.rebelion.la/contact-us" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">send me a message here</a> or on <a href="https://https//www.linkedin.com/comm/mynetwork/discovery-see-all?usecase=PEOPLE_FOLLOWS&amp;followMember=adrianescutia" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LinkedIn</a>. I'm always happy to help. 😊</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="references">References<a href="https://escutia.me/adrian/fixing-vscode-code.exe--exec-format-error-in-wsl#references" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to References" title="Direct link to References">​</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Stack Overflow: <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/a/76975972/5078874" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Cannot run any WSL commands/Not able to make WSL work with VS Code (Exec Format Error)</a>.</li>
<li>GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/microsoft/WSL/issues/8952#issuecomment-1568212651" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">WSL2 (Preview) cannot run .exe files: exec format error: wsl.exe</a>.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>vscode</category>
            <category>wsl</category>
            <category>linux</category>
            <category>troubleshooting</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A slight pivot in the Airgap Bundler]]></title>
            <link>https://escutia.me/adrian/update-about-airgap-tool</link>
            <guid>https://escutia.me/adrian/update-about-airgap-tool</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 12:01:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[In my experiments journey, I discovered Refine, and decided to pivot slightly in the airgap tool MVP with SBOMs, Refine, and Docusaurus.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>A slight pivot in the airgap bundler tool MVP to add SBOMs.</strong></p>
<p>This weekend has been a breakthrough—not necessarily in pushing my tools forward for the community, but in expanding my knowledge. I discovered <a href="https://refine.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Refine</a>, and it is honestly a game changer (for a backend developer like me). It lets me scaffold React projects with a robust, reusable architecture, perfect for developers and solopreneurs. Instead of wasting time reinventing the wheel, you get a clean structure right from the start. Combine this with <a href="https://docusaurus.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Docusaurus</a> in a mono-repo setup, and you've got limitless potential. The combination of these two can redefine how we manage documentation and dashboards in our projects.</p>
<p>That said, I'm going to dedicate another weekend (and nights) to improving the <a href="https://k1s.sh/airgap" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">airgap bundler</a> MVP or <strong>SABOR</strong> (flavor in Spanish, <strong>S</strong>oftware <strong>A</strong>irgap <strong>B</strong>ill <strong>o</strong>f Materials <strong>R</strong>esolver) as I like to call it (check the demo video below 👇🏻). I have decided to pivot slightly, the community has given great feedback so far, but after thinking it through, I realized tools like <a href="https://github.com/containers/skopeo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Skopeo</a> and <a href="https://github.com/google/go-containerregistry/blob/main/cmd/crane/doc/crane.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Crane</a> might already be top choices for many. And while the CLI MVP has gotten positive reception, we all know the problem with CLI tools—they are great until you're swimming in flags and options that are impossible to remember.</p>
<p>So here's the new direction: I'm going to double down on leveraging <a href="https://www.ntia.gov/page/software-bill-materials" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SBOMs</a>. I've started with <a href="https://cyclonedx.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CycloneDX</a>, and later, introduce <a href="https://spdx.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SPDX</a> into the mix. This will add more value, making the tool not just another CLI alternative, but one that builds on transparency and security by integrating software bills of materials into the process. Think of it as creating the ultimate airgap distribution package that's not just about bundling images, but about understanding and orchestrating them across multiple environments—whether it is hybrid cloud or airgapped scenarios.</p>
<p><strong>Why an airgap tool?</strong> Because it's a critical piece in the puzzle of secure software distribution, and deploying cloud native and Kubernetes clusters in airgapped environments is a common challenge.</p>
<p><strong>Why SBOMs?</strong> They are the key to understanding what is in your software, and they are crucial for security, compliance, and transparency. By integrating SBOMs into the airgap bundler, we're not just creating a tool; we're creating a movement. A movement towards better software practices, better security, and better collaboration, a <strong>Rebel movement</strong>!</p>
<p>Not to mention, that the Kubernetes community is already pushing for SBOMs with <a href="https://kubernetes-sigs.github.io/bom/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">K8s BOM tool</a>, and with the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/05/12/executive-order-on-improving-the-nations-cybersecurity/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">executive order</a> from the White House, it's clear that SBOMs are the future. So why not start now?</p>
<p>It is clear where the industry is heading, and I want to be at the forefront of it. I want to build tools that are not just useful, but essential. Tools that are not just for the community, but by the community. Tools that are not just for today, but for the future.</p>
<p>Here's a sneak peek of the new direction:</p>
<video width="620" autoplay="" loop="" muted=""><source src="/assets/medias/k1s-airgap-bundler-demo-s-1ae3e7b6e52f59990ab6ab050da6c799.mp4" type="video/mp4"><p>Your browser does not support the video tag.</p></video>
<p>Don't worry, though. I'm not abandoning the CLI. I'm simply evolving it into something smarter, more intuitive, and community-driven.</p>
<p>Let's keep this momentum going—together, we're building something amazing. Your feedback is crucial, so don't hesitate to share your thoughts. Let's go, Rebels! ✊🏻</p>
<p>Stay tuned for more updates, don't forget to subscribe to the <a href="https://go.rebelion.la/k1s-news" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">newsletter</a> for the latest news and updates. And if you haven't already, check out the <a href="https://k1s.sh/airgap" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">airgap bundler</a> MVP and let me know what you think.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Airgap</category>
            <category>SBOM</category>
            <category>Kubernetes</category>
            <category>Refine</category>
            <category>Docusaurus</category>
            <category>MVP</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The State of Software Development in 2024 from StackOverflow]]></title>
            <link>https://escutia.me/adrian/the-state-of-software-development-in-2024</link>
            <guid>https://escutia.me/adrian/the-state-of-software-development-in-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 02:10:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The State of Software Development in 2024: Insights from StackOverflow's Annual Developer Survey]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Software development is a dynamic field that constantly evolves with new technologies, tools, and practices. To understand the current state of software development, Stack Overflow conducts an annual survey of developers worldwide. The 2024 survey, featuring over 65,000 participants from 185 countries, provides valuable insights into the trends shaping the industry. This article explores the key findings of the survey and what they mean for developers and the future of software development.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="The State of Software Development in 2024" src="https://escutia.me/assets/images/the-state-of-software-development-in-2024-c4b0ae0ba33fb6a96f3085f8c832de5d.png" width="1326" height="780" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="key-findings">Key Findings<a href="https://escutia.me/adrian/the-state-of-software-development-in-2024#key-findings" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Key Findings" title="Direct link to Key Findings">​</a></h2>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="javascript-reigns-supreme">JavaScript Reigns Supreme<a href="https://escutia.me/adrian/the-state-of-software-development-in-2024#javascript-reigns-supreme" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to JavaScript Reigns Supreme" title="Direct link to JavaScript Reigns Supreme">​</a></h3>
<p>JavaScript popularity continues its dominance as the most popular programming language, with 62% of respondents using it regularly. Its versatility and extensive ecosystem make it a favorite among developers for both front-end and back-end development. Other popular languages include HTML/CSS (53%), Python (51%), SQL (51%), and TypeScript (38.5%).</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="trust-in-ai-a-double-edged-sword">Trust in AI: A Double-Edged Sword<a href="https://escutia.me/adrian/the-state-of-software-development-in-2024#trust-in-ai-a-double-edged-sword" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Trust in AI: A Double-Edged Sword" title="Direct link to Trust in AI: A Double-Edged Sword">​</a></h3>
<p>AI tools are increasingly integrated into developers' workflows, with 76% using or planning to use them. However, trust in these tools remains low. Only 43% of developers trust the accuracy of AI tools, and nearly half (45%) believe AI struggles with complex tasks. This highlights a significant gap between the adoption of AI and confidence in its capabilities.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="productivity-boosts-and-learning-aids">Productivity Boosts and Learning Aids<a href="https://escutia.me/adrian/the-state-of-software-development-in-2024#productivity-boosts-and-learning-aids" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Productivity Boosts and Learning Aids" title="Direct link to Productivity Boosts and Learning Aids">​</a></h3>
<p>Despite trust issues, developers acknowledge the productivity benefits of AI. 81% report that AI tools help them work more efficiently, and 71% of beginners use AI to accelerate their learning. This underscores the potential of AI to streamline coding processes and enhance educational experiences.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="ethical-concerns-with-ai">Ethical Concerns with AI<a href="https://escutia.me/adrian/the-state-of-software-development-in-2024#ethical-concerns-with-ai" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Ethical Concerns with AI" title="Direct link to Ethical Concerns with AI">​</a></h3>
<p>Developers are increasingly aware of the ethical implications of AI. The top concerns include the potential for AI to spread misinformation (79%), issues with data attribution (65%), and biases that fail to represent diverse viewpoints (50%). Addressing these ethical challenges is crucial for the responsible development and deployment of AI technologies.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-rise-of-online-learning">The Rise of Online Learning<a href="https://escutia.me/adrian/the-state-of-software-development-in-2024#the-rise-of-online-learning" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Rise of Online Learning" title="Direct link to The Rise of Online Learning">​</a></h3>
<p>Online resources remain the go-to for developers looking to learn new skills. 82% of respondents use online materials, with technical documentation (83%) and Stack Overflow (80%) being the most popular sources. Additionally, 37% of developers use AI tools for learning, indicating a growing trend towards AI-assisted education.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="cloud-platform-preferences">Cloud Platform Preferences<a href="https://escutia.me/adrian/the-state-of-software-development-in-2024#cloud-platform-preferences" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Cloud Platform Preferences" title="Direct link to Cloud Platform Preferences">​</a></h3>
<p>When it comes to cloud platforms, AWS leads the pack with 48% of developers using it. Microsoft Azure and Google Cloud are also popular, with usage rates of 28% and 25%, respectively. The growing adoption of these platforms reflects the increasing reliance on cloud services for scalable and flexible infrastructure solutions.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="postgresql-tops-the-database-charts">PostgreSQL Tops the Database Charts<a href="https://escutia.me/adrian/the-state-of-software-development-in-2024#postgresql-tops-the-database-charts" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to PostgreSQL Tops the Database Charts" title="Direct link to PostgreSQL Tops the Database Charts">​</a></h3>
<p>PostgreSQL is the most popular database among developers, favored by 49% of respondents. However, beginners prefer MySQL (45%) and SQLite (36%), suggesting that ease of use and familiarity play significant roles in database choice during the learning phase.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="vs-code-the-ide-of-choice">VS Code: The IDE of Choice<a href="https://escutia.me/adrian/the-state-of-software-development-in-2024#vs-code-the-ide-of-choice" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to VS Code: The IDE of Choice" title="Direct link to VS Code: The IDE of Choice">​</a></h3>
<p>Visual Studio Code dominates the IDE landscape, used by 74% of developers. Its popularity can be attributed to its powerful features, extensive plugin ecosystem, and strong community support. Visual Studio, the next most popular IDE, is used by 29% of respondents.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="10-key-takeaways">10 Key Takeaways<a href="https://escutia.me/adrian/the-state-of-software-development-in-2024#10-key-takeaways" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 10 Key Takeaways" title="Direct link to 10 Key Takeaways">​</a></h2>
<ol>
<li>JavaScript Dominance: JavaScript is the most popular programming language, used by 62% of respondents.</li>
<li>AI Trust Issues: Only 43% of developers trust AI tools, with 45% believing AI struggles with complex tasks.</li>
<li>Database Preferences: PostgreSQL is the top database among developers, while beginners prefer MySQL and SQLite.</li>
<li>AI and Productivity: 81% of developers find AI tools boost productivity; 71% of beginners use AI to speed up learning.</li>
<li>Ethical Concerns: Top AI ethical issues include misinformation (79%) and bias (50%).</li>
<li>Learning Resources: 82% of developers use online resources for learning, with Stack Overflow and technical documentation being top choices.</li>
<li>Cloud Platforms: AWS leads as the most used cloud platform (48%), with Azure and Google Cloud also gaining ground.</li>
<li>AI Adoption: 76% of developers are using or planning to use AI tools, up from 70% last year.</li>
<li>IDE Usage: VS Code is the leading IDE, used by 74% of developers.</li>
<li>Work Communication: Microsoft Teams is the preferred tool for professional developers, while Discord is popular among those learning to code.</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-future-of-software-development">The Future of Software Development<a href="https://escutia.me/adrian/the-state-of-software-development-in-2024#the-future-of-software-development" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Future of Software Development" title="Direct link to The Future of Software Development">​</a></h2>
<p>The survey provides valuable insights into the current state of software development and offers a glimpse into the future. As AI continues to play a significant role in software development, developers must address ethical concerns and trust issues. Learning resources and cloud platforms will continue to evolve, shaping the way developers learn and build applications. The rise of AI tools and IDEs like VS Code will drive productivity and innovation in the industry. By staying informed and adapting to these trends, developers can navigate the changing landscape of software development in 2024 and beyond.</p>
<p>Get ready for the future of software development!</p>
<p>References:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://survey.stackoverflow.co/2024/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Stack Overflow Developer Survey 2024</a></li>
<li><a href="https://unsplash.com/@dengxiangs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Cover Image Source</a></li>
<li><a href="https://stackoverflow.blog/2024/07/24/developers-want-more-more-more-the-2024-results-from-stack-overflow-s-annual-developer-survey/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2024 Results from Stack Overflow Annual Developer Survey</a></li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Software Development</category>
            <category>Stack Overflow</category>
            <category>AI</category>
            <category>PostgreSQL</category>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
            <category>VS Code</category>
            <category>Online Learning</category>
            <category>AI Tools</category>
            <category>Database Preferences</category>
            <category>Cloud Platforms</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Strategies for continuous learning and professional growth]]></title>
            <link>https://escutia.me/adrian/strategies-for-continuous-learning-and-professional-growth</link>
            <guid>https://escutia.me/adrian/strategies-for-continuous-learning-and-professional-growth</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 10:39:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Discover effective strategies for continuous learning and professional growth. Learn how personal projects and innovation can propel your career forward.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ever wondered how some people seem to know so much about so many different topics and tools? A couple of my friends have asked me this, especially considering the variety of things I juggle daily at work. Some have even asked me if I have a twin or a clone, or if I ever sleep. The truth is, I'm just a regular person who's passionate about learning and growing. I'm always looking for new ways to improve my skills and knowledge.</p>
<p>Here's my secret: I don't wait for my employer to invest in my professional growth or pay for certifications. Sure, they might provide some learning resources, but those are often too generic. Real learning requires diving deeper, getting your hands dirty, making mistakes, making big efforts, and sometimes sacrificing things like sleep.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-power-of-projects-for-professional-growth">The Power of Projects for Professional Growth<a href="https://escutia.me/adrian/strategies-for-continuous-learning-and-professional-growth#the-power-of-projects-for-professional-growth" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Power of Projects for Professional Growth" title="Direct link to The Power of Projects for Professional Growth">​</a></h2>
<p>For me, projects are the best way to learn something new. Think about an intern who starts knowing almost nothing. They learn from senior colleagues. But when you're a senior, you need to find new ways to keep growing. Maybe that's through internal gigs at your company or innovation hackathons. The key is to see your projects implemented and released. That's real motivation - seeing your ideas come to life.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="learning-by-doing-to-gain-real-world-experience">Learning by Doing to gain Real-world experience<a href="https://escutia.me/adrian/strategies-for-continuous-learning-and-professional-growth#learning-by-doing-to-gain-real-world-experience" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Learning by Doing to gain Real-world experience" title="Direct link to Learning by Doing to gain Real-world experience">​</a></h3>
<p>I learn by doing. I don't just read about things. I try them out. I experiment. I make mistakes. I learn from those mistakes. I try again. I keep trying until I get it right. I don't give up. I don't get discouraged. I keep going. I keep learning. I keep growing.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="creating-toy-projects">Creating "Toy Projects"<a href="https://escutia.me/adrian/strategies-for-continuous-learning-and-professional-growth#creating-toy-projects" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Creating &quot;Toy Projects&quot;" title="Direct link to Creating &quot;Toy Projects&quot;">​</a></h2>
<p>To learn more about specific things, I create "toy projects." These are small projects that solve the personal problems I face daily. If I see potential in these projects, I keep improving them, learning more and adding features. The challenge, of course, is switching contexts. At work, I deal with many different problems, so I build different "toys" and try to connect them like LEGO pieces to create a more robust solution.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="reading-and-watching">Reading and Watching<a href="https://escutia.me/adrian/strategies-for-continuous-learning-and-professional-growth#reading-and-watching" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Reading and Watching" title="Direct link to Reading and Watching">​</a></h2>
<p>I also read a lot. I read books, articles, and blog posts. Mainly, I listen to podcasts, but listening carefully, and gather information and ideas that connect with my projects. I follow people who inspire me and share their knowledge. I'm always looking for new ways to learn and grow.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="your-turn">Your Turn<a href="https://escutia.me/adrian/strategies-for-continuous-learning-and-professional-growth#your-turn" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Your Turn" title="Direct link to Your Turn">​</a></h2>
<p>What about you? How do you grow professionally and learn new things? Share your strategies—I'd love to hear them!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Continuous learning</category>
            <category>Professional growth</category>
            <category>Personal projects</category>
            <category>Self-improvement</category>
            <category>Learning strategies</category>
            <category>Skill development</category>
            <category>Career advancement</category>
            <category>Toy projects</category>
            <category>Innovation</category>
            <category>Hackathons</category>
            <category>Real-world experience</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>